objectivity battle. Here's the bitter
pill. Objectivity has no place in
personal relations. I'm sorry. The
relational answer to who's right and
who's wrong is who gives a What
matters is how are you and I going to
work this thing in a way that's going to
work for us. And proving who's right and
who's wrong is not the way to do that.
Let me give you an example of the new
world. Her to him, you're a reckless
driver. Him to her, you're overly
nervous. How many of us have been
through this one? Everybody starts
marshalling their evidence and arguing
their case. No, you're nervous. You're
nervous about this. No, no, you're
reckless. You tailgate. That's an
objectivity. Who's right, who's wrong?
After one session with me, true story,
her to him, "Honey, start with that."
Changing energy. "Honey, I know you love
me. Right or wrong, maybe I'm overly
nervous or whatever." See, she just
takes the whole battle off the table by
talking subjectively. "Maybe I'm overly
nervous. Nevertheless, when you tailgate
and you go switch lanes and you speed
up, I get crazy. I get scared." Now,
"when you're driving on your own, I
worry about it's your life. When I'm
next to you, you don't really want me
sitting here being terrified the whole
time we're driving. As a favor to me,
could you please slow down and drive
more conservatively?" And him to her,
"Okay." And he does. What might have
been a fight that lasted 40 years is
done in 15 minutes because it moves out
of objective, who's the authority, who's
right, who's wrong, what's fair, what's
unfair, and it becomes relational. We're
a team. You love me. As a favor to me,
could you? Sure. New world.